Sebastian Durandeu

Senior Software Engineer

London, N22, UK

+44 07427 719875

sebastian.durandeu@gmail.com

S sdurandeu

y sebadurandeu

in sebastiandurandeu

About Me

For 10+ years I have helped multiple Fortune 500 companies and startups build software solutions acting as full-stack developer, team lead and customer advocate. I have experience leading both on-site and distributed teams, making sure delivery goes according to plan and meets customer expectations. I believe my greatest strengths are my organization and attention to detail and best practices, together with excellent communication and reporting skills.

Skills

The technologies and frameworks I have worked most with include:

- .NET Framework and the Microsoft Web Stack (ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, Web Api, etc.)
- Cloud Platforms and Services (Microsoft Azure and Amazon Web Services)
- Web standards (HTTP, REST, HTML5, etc.)
- Javascript and Node.js
- Hybrid mobile apps (Cordova, Ionic, etc.)
- Database systems (MS SQL Server and Analysis Services, MySQL, MongoDB, etc.)
- Continuous Integration and Delivery automation (TeamCity, Selenium, PowerShell, etc.)

My experience includes:

- Team leading (make sure everyone is doing what is best for the project outcome)
- Agile project estimation and planning
- Business analysis (understand and anticipate customer needs)
- · Code reviewing
- Performance evaluation and mentoring of developers

Experience

<u>Southworks</u>

Apr 2017 - Ongoing

Software consultancy firm specialized in helping companies adopt emerging technologies

Principal Software Engineer (London, UK)

Managed remotely a development team (5) to re-engineer a core statistics system from a US sports company and migrate it to the cloud (Microsoft Azure). Project design and planning. Main interface with the customer with regular on-site meetings for progress reporting. 1-on-1 meetings with developers for performance evaluation and mentoring.

Vinti Apr 2016 - Mar 2017

FinTech startup - mobile app to solve everyday payments with a smart, user-friendly approach (more info in Spanish <u>here</u> and <u>here</u>)

Lead Engineer (Buenos Aires, Argentina)

Joined the co-founders as first employee to build and grow the payments platform. Full-stack engineer in charge of the Cordova/Ionic mobile app with a Node.js backend hosted in Amazon Web Services. Infrastructure design, maintenance and security audits. Also worked on product design, customer support and sales.

Southworks Jun 2007 - Apr 2016

Software consultancy firm specialized in helping companies adopt emerging technologies

Principal Software Engineer (Buenos Aires, Argentina)

Member of the Delivery team, in charge of resource allocation, project forecasting and monitoring.
 Recruiting and performance reviews of developers. Support account managers with new opportunities (pre-sales).

• Technical lead for developing and maintaining one of Microsoft's core marketing and documentation sites running using Microsoft Azure cloud services. Requirements include high availability and scalability, CDN and content caching, localization, among others. Project also included developing a documentation publishing and maintenance workflow using automated deployment infrastructure.

Lead Software Engineer (Redmond, US)

- 3 months on-site at Microsoft headquarters working in the the <u>Azure Marketplace</u> engineering team. Developed a continuous testing infrastructure based on Selenium and the TeamCity API to validate partners' listings and integrations.
- Helped Microsoft internal teams deliver <u>keynote demos</u> () highlighting the very latest in technology to be presented during the <u>BUILD 2012</u> and <u>2013</u> annual conferences for developers. Provided support to presenters from the backstage.

Technical Writer/Software Engineer (Buenos Aires, Argentina)

- Developed technical guidance, toolkits and APIs for Microsoft Developer Experience (DX) Division to help the developer community adopt new Microsoft technologies and frameworks (e.g. hands-on labs for Microsoft Azure Training Kit, DinnerNow or OData API for Visual Studio Team Foundation Service).
- Helped a top pharmaceutical company develop a company-wide identity platform, based on claimsbased identity and Microsoft Active Directory Federation Services (ADFS).

Side Projects

<u>Toptal Member</u>

Jan 2016 - Ongoing

Premium Freelance Platform

Completed the recruiting process and joined the platform, but did not apply for any project due to lack of availability. Public profile can be viewed <u>here</u>.

TiendaNube Rating Store App

TiendaNube provides a complete e-commerce platform for small retailers (similar to Shopify or Magento)

Designed and developed an app that allows users to add a rating and comments widget to their store. The app can be installed through the <u>app store</u> for a monthly fee and is available both in Spanish and Portuguese. It is developed in Node.js (Express) and MongoDB and hosted in Amazon Web Services.

Publications

- Reviewed technical books for Packt Publishing: <u>Azure Storage Essentials</u> and <u>Implementing Azure Solutions</u>
- Personal blog in Spanish including software development and other stuff (outdated)
- Sentiment analysis in microblogging: a practical implementation. M Cohen, P Damiani, S Durandeu, R
 Navas, H Merlino, XVII Congreso Argentino de Ciencias de la Computación, 2011 (<u>link</u>)

Education

Software Engineer

2004 - 2011

University of Buenos Aires - Grade +8/10

One year as teaching assistant in Dața Oṛgañiĉațiõñ class. Some topics covered by the subject included data organization structures and algorithms (B-trees, Hashes, etc.), text retrieval engines and data compression.

Languages

English Bilingual - Certificate in Advanced English (<u>CAE</u>)

French Basic - Diplôme d'Études en Langue Française B1 (DELF)

Spanish Native

More

Three books I have read this year: <u>The Manager's Path</u> by Camille Fournier, <u>Shantaram</u> by Gregory David Roberts, and <u>Sapiens</u> by Yuval Noah Harari